# Venu K

# **DC** Analyst

Email: venukodandaram@gmail.com

**Mobile**: +91 9740173915

Address: #526, Sri Lakshmi Nilaya, 10th main road, Bharat Nagar, Bangalore: 560091

**Summary:** With a solid 4-year tenure from December 2019 to December 2023, I possess expertise in development of Crystal Reports, Qlik Sense, ETL with Informatica and data validation. My experience includes a year as a Data Science Intern at Flux Auto and a 6-month role as a Data Science Consultant at Rubixe, focusing on deep learning, data modeling, and machine learning. This track record underscores my commitment to ongoing learning and my capacity to contribute effectively to diverse projects.

#### **Education:**

## **Bachelor Of Engineering (Electronics and Communication)**

Dayananda Sagar Academy of Technology and Management (VTU Affiliated), Bangalore

**Skills:** Data Science, SQL, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Python, Qlik Sense, Qlik View, Crystal Reports Developer, ETL, Alteryx (Basics), POSTMAN, Converge Health Safety, Oracle Argus.

# **Work Experience:**

## Flux Auto Experience

Role: Data Science Intern | Dec 2019 – Dec 2020

**Description:** Collaborated with US and European clients on Image and Lidar data processing. Conducted Data Annotation using VGG tool and cloud platforms for both U.S. and Indian datasets. Developed diverse deep learning models, adjusting parameters, learning rates, epochs, and accuracy for image classification and detection. Proficient in working with Lidar data and PCDs using Unity Hub.

### **Deloitte Experience:**

1. Client: Regeneron (Leading Biotechnology and Pharmaceutical Company)

**Role:** Crystal Reports and SQL Developer | Jan 2021 – May 2022

**Description:** Designed and developed crystal reports based on business requirements. Proficient in SQL and SAP HANA, with expertise in SAP Crystal Reports for template development. Successfully deployed reports using POSTMAN Commands, resolved issues, and contributed to Auto Report distribution with Python.

2. Client: Daiichi Sankyo (Leading Biotechnology and Pharmaceutical Company)

Role: Argus Application Support (AMS Team member) | May 2022 – October 2022

**Description:** Implemented front-end and backend changes in response to client requests, ensuring smooth business operations by resolving incidents and Change Requests. Conducted Impact analysis on License, Reporting rules, Advance conditions, and Advance condition query set as per client requirements. Successfully implemented Advance Auto

Labelling CR in the Argus Application as requested by the client. Managed cache clear and maintenance activities of Argus application servers on a weekly basis, gaining exposure to WHO Drug code upgrade in the Argus application.

**3. Client**: Ford Motor Company

Role: Qlik View/ Qlik Sense Developer | Nov 2022 – Dec 2023

**Description:** Gathered KPI requirements, designed wireframes, and developed end-to-end KPI visuals in Qlik Sense. Proficient in SQL for data retrieval, QVD file creation, and overcoming Qlik Sense limitations. Conducted unit testing, prepared integration steps, and delivered complex KPIs adhering to Deloitte standards. Led innovative development, including feature buttons and a run chart, optimizing Qlik Sense performance and took complete owner and responsibility on assigned KPIs in DEV, VAL, and PROD Environments.

### **Professional Affiliations / Certifications:**

- "Data Science Foundation" from IABAC (International Association for Business Analytics Certification).
- "Certified Data Scientist" from IABAC (International Association for Business Analytics Certification).
- Statistics for Data Science and Business Analysis from Udemy.
- different technologies or languages like SQL, Scala, Spark, Data warehousing, Azure from Udemy.
- Machine Learning from Coursera (offered by Sandford University (Andrew Ng)).
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning from deeplearning.ai.

### **Key Achievements:**

- Achieved the honor of Star Performer.
- Received the Spot Award in February 2022 and April 2023.
- Received multiple appreciations, including "Champion", "Asset of the Project," "Going above and beyond", "Proud to have you in the team," and "High-quality data and code delivery with simply exponential."
- Presented my academic project in EL Asia 2019 International Exhibition.
- Completed Internship successfully in RTL Design using Verilog HDL at Innovations Labs, DSI.